São Paulo,
almost 13 million inhabitants.
This part of my story began here.
In autumn.
Sampa in autumn means
rush, reality, scurrying, umbrella,
coat and sunscreen,
altogether.
The weather changes.
Life's hectic and you've gotta be ready.
Look at Paulista Avenue.
Imagine how many dreams
you can find there.
For example, this was
my last day of work at a law office.
It seemed fancy to say this was a job,
but it was
a college extracurricular activity.
I dreamt about being an intern there,
but there's a crowd vying
for the same spot.
A huge, crazy competition.
Was I sad? A little,
but not discouraged.
That's me,
Anna Júlia.
I like justice, working, joy.
Not music.
I don't like music.
I didn't want this for my life.
On the other hand, I wanted this!
I want to be exactly like them
when I'm older. It's a lot of power.
This is João Paulo,
- a street musician.
- Hey, dude!
Jeez, he turned my world upside down...
Come on, guys. Let's help!
Put some money in here!
Let's enjoy some music, get to know art.
The Pedros!
Oh, no. Here comes another fantasy.
Double coffee to wake up
Focus and faith I will succeed
It's not long before I graduate
So many things, but we're here
And it's written
That the expert will arrive
It's true, it worked out
The Black woman will be in charge
I came to sing
My journey
With magic
Of being who I am
- I have love in my chest
- And I do it my way
- Axé in living
- So I can dawn
Come on, guys!
Good morning.
Go, the more you live the song
Go, the more you understand
Open my heart
You know you can't be careless
That this big world comes
And shakes who sleeps
No one can beat me
It requires a lot of talent
And direction and luck
- I have love in my chest
- And I do it my way
- Axé in living
- So I can dawn
Go, the more you live the song
Go, the more you understand
Open my heart
Wait. I don't like music.
An Unforgettable Year AUTUMN
BASED ON THE WORK OF
BABI DEWET
MOM - DON'T ANSWER
There's this situation too.
I'll explain it soon.
Sorry I'm late, Mr. Rui.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Hey, sorry.
- Joice?
- Good morning.
Hi!
Whose stuff is this?
Heitor?
Hey...
Can you move your suitcase, so I can sit?
Unfortunately, I don't have
anywhere to put it.
Go find a chair.
Hey, artist!
Can you stop the noise?
I'm trying to watch the game.
Hey, kid.
Here.
Thanks, Mr. Marcílio.
Listen...
I heard the last band here
had concerts and recorded albums.
The Vultures of the Next Day!
They played at Covers Square
and made a music video that went viral.
Hi.
Came to perform?
In order to play here, you need
to get a pass at the end of the line
- with Baby, who is beside Junk.
- The wonderful Junk!
If you want, come back at dawn.
There's no line nor audience.
But you can play.
I won't even say a word.
- Come on! Guys, stay!
- I'm leaving, JP.
Where are you going?
Go get coffee and come back.
I'll wait in line. I'll stay here...
CULTURAL TURN FESTIVAL
ONLY ORIGINAL SONGS
This will be a trend.
Hi, Dad. Did something happen?
Yes. I miss you a lot, kiddo!
And I'd like to know if you want a ride.
I'm driving a nice client
near your office.
- We could celebrate, right?
- There's nothing to celebrate.
But you should, Anna Júlia!
Girl, now you'll have more free time.
Dindinha, tell her.
- Hey, girl! How are you?
- Hi!
Your father told me everything.
Enjoy those young years, girl!
Only you would make me talk
to a passenger.
- Are you driving? It's dangerous.
- No, baby.
We're stuck in a traffic jam.
I just called
to see if everything is okay.
It will be, Dad.
Since you work nearby,
come by my house later.
- It's in More Than One Squat.
- Thanks. I'll be there.
- Bye, beautiful girl.
- Bye, honey!
- Take care of him.
- Love you.
Bye, guys!
MESSING AROUND
IN THE OFFICE
Go mess around at home, bye.
Attention, everyone.
I've got news for you.
Well...
We lost an intern.
So, I decided to expand
the internship program
to hire one of you to replace him.
This means that this is not the last day
for any of you.
And for those who want
to start a career at this firm,
the good news is...
you have more time to impress me.
- Joice?
- Yes?
- Grab me a cappuccino, please.
- Sure.
No, allow me!
You changed the Wi-Fi password?
What?
Mr. Zé Carlos, I'm a customer today.
It's a cappuccino.
Fancy stuff. Tell me the password.
WI-FI PASSWORD
BUY A CAKE
Empathy! I like you.
Excuse me. Is this the line?
Oh, my God! He's so hot.
Why did I need just one cappuccino?
Is this a cappuccino?
- Yes, it is.
- Would you sell it to me?
I'll give you the money,
and you give me the goods.
Nice to meet you.
My name is João Paulo. You are?
Thanks.
We did business,
and you didn't tell me your name.
Hey, don't forget it, okay? João Paulo!
In honor of the two Beatles.
- Are you in line?
- No.
DESTINY MAKES YOUR PATH RHYME
WITH MINE
IT'S LIKE EMICIDA'S VERSE,
WHEN YOU SEE IT, IT HAS ALREADY HAPPENED.
You're fast.
So, pick me.
This internship is all I ever wanted.
- I know.
- I won't let you down.
You must work hard, Anna. Things here
are not easy. You saw the competition.
You must pay attention to everything.
Especially to the details.
Be careful! If you break it,
you need to give me another one.
The stairs! Watch your step.
Hey! Stop it! Excuse me. It won't pass.
- For God's sake.
- Stop complaining.
Excuse me, man!
- Watch the stairs!
- What's going on?
What's this?
Watch the door.
Are we moving and no one told me?
The band is over, right?
We're moving back to Jaú.
The band is over?
What do you mean, Pedro Jorge?
Excuse me.
- Who decided that?
- I did, right?
We talked about the festival.
It's our chance.
The festival only accepts original songs.
We have none.
But we are good!
We are good,
but have we written anything yet?
- No.
- Right.
- How will we win the festival?
- Relax.
Calm down, brothers.
Isn't that what we are? Brothers!
The Pedros Plus One.
I'm not Pedro!
But you are my brothers, man.
Stay!
There's cheese in the fridge.
Is it the mess?
- No.
- I know.
This has nothing to do
with this mess or with you.
- We are the problem.
- Guys.
My mom is in a hurry. Bye, JP!
See you!
The dream is over.
Go ahead!
I'll stay here.
I'll stay and write a song.
You'll see!
I'm gonna prove to you that one João Paulo
is much more powerful
than three Pedros together!
One!
"THE PEDROS PLUS ONE"
THE BEST COVER BAND IN JAÚ
That day felt like my dream was starting
to become a reality.
As if it was the first day
of the rest of my life.
An orderly, organized life,
with everything in place.
The dream of a Black girl
who loves justice
and was born to be a lawyer.
All set.
Time to sleep, to eat,
to wake up, no music, no mess,
no despair, no nostalgia, just will.
The will to speed up even more
and finally be able to say,
"Nice to meet you. I'm Anna Júlia,
a lawyer." This is so me, right?
Will you be a singer, daughter?
I love singing with you.
Will you sing one more with me?
Will you?
Let's do it.
Beautiful!
Dad, can I borrow your black jacket?
Good morning to you too, honey.
Come have breakfast.
I don't have time. The jacket?
- I gave it away.
- Dad! Not that jacket!
The guy was freezing to death.
I couldn't let him.
He was alone, abandoned.
Oh, my God.
- Only you would do that. I'm off to work.
- Okay.
Aninha, what about the coffee?
At least have the milk
I prepared to celebrate yesterday.
Please.
That's it. Listen to your father!
- Okay, Dad. Look.
- As if.
- Yummy.
- There's no napkin.
No, let me do that. You're late.
God... I love
when you treat me like a baby!
- Love you.
- Cookie?
I'll take it for the ride.
Anna?
MOM - DON'T ANSWER
Answer it. Deal with it once and for all.
This has already been dealt with.
Anna!
LAW SCHOOL
I don't think you get it, Anna Júlia.
I'd like to know if you'd defend someone
who did something very wrong,
like stealing some old man's pension.
I got it, Heitor. And I've answered you,
but I can slow down so you can understand.
I wouldn't defend the person
or what they did.
I'd defend
my client's constitutional rights.
The constitutional rights of your client?
You're talking like a lawyer,
and we're just freshman.
- Take it slow, Anna Júlia.
- I'm in a hurry, Heitor.
That's because I'm a woman
ahead of my time.
My professor and maybe future boss.
Gotta please her, right?
I tried to make it worthwhile
I didn't care about problems
I thought I was enough
But I wasn't for you
I tried to be the perfect guy
I did things your way
I wanted to be more important
But I wasn't for you
It did last, tell me why
You wasted so much time here
I'll do you a favor and vanish
I was just another one for you
I don't know if it was due neediness
Or lack of choice
I just know that I felt love
Too bad, I was the only one who felt love
Sorry.
What do I do with plans
For the coming years?
I swear I don't know
I just know I felt love
Too bad, I was the only one who felt love
I was the only one who felt love
Thank you!
- Thanks for saving me that time.
- No problem.
If you need anything, tell me.
- Don't you wanna write a song for me?
- What?
Nothing. I'm kidding. What's your name?
- Wesley.
- Wesley!
- Nice to meet you.
- João Paulo.
We need this case.
- Know anything about these squatters?
- Not yet.
- I know it's nearby.
- I need a connection there.
Sorry, I overheard your conversation...
Hello?
No, I'm not busy. Go on.
I love the scarf! Yes, I'm listening.
MORE THAN ONE SQUAT
FEARLESS PEOPLE
- Hey, excuse me.
- Sorry...
We have these food staples
that we deliver to families.
There's a meeting now.
We'll go to the kitchen later to see...
Hey! I'm Anna Júlia, do you remember me?
Guilherme's daughter. The driver.
We talked on the phone.
- I do remember. The working girl.
- Thanks.
Tell me, are you here to volunteer?
Sure, who do I talk to?
To me. I was one of the first
in this squat.
I can't talk to you right now
because I have a meeting.
- Will you come back later?
- I will!
- I'll be waiting for you.
- Count on me.
Look how everything can change
suddenly in autumn.
Oh, my...
I told you, right?
Oh, no!
I need to go to work!
- Right now?
- Yeah.
- And I can't be late.
- But you also can't make the rain stop,
can you?
Oh, rain, come and tell me if I can...
- No!
- I know. It touches deep inside, right?
There's also another rain song I love.
It's by Gil. He is a god.
I have many gods and goddesses too.
Maria Bethânia. Elza Soares...
No, that's not what I meant.
I don't like music, got it?
- How don't you like music?
- I don't.
No way.
It's like you don't like chocolate,
spooning or the acai berry.
- Impossible.
- You're not making any sense.
If I sang you a song by Melodia
You'd follow me like this
Like Cartola and his roses
Wonderful, like Jorge and Gil
And Lady Gaga would migrate
From her island to our Brazil
Singing a song by IZA
Or M.I.A. like Caetano in a drumbeat
There's Sabotage and Rita Lee
Chico Science and Nação Zumbi
And so many people I love
And I don't even sing in this song
They're great artists,
but I don't like music.
I don't believe it. Prove it.
- How?
- I don't know. Sing.
Music makes me cry
I don't know how to sing
It makes me soft, I lose my gaze
Music sticks
Glues in my mind
I get all wrong, I have to study
Music reminds me
Of things I don't wanna see
And it makes me sad
Sad without knowing
Are you gonna say
that a samba doesn't make you happy?
Tell me you don't get excited
listening to Elis?
I've got to go. It's almost time.
Are you gonna say that at the end
of a show you don't ask for an encore?
Stop messing with my head, please!
I don't like music,
but I can't say the same about you.
Where are you going?
We've done business, almost kissed
and you haven't said your name!
Anna Júlia. My name is Anna Júlia.
Anna Júlia?
Your name is a song. Anna Júlia!
Those who see you passing by me...
Hey, Anna Júlia!
Wow!
You don't know what just happened!
Excuse me, Sophia!
I really want to talk to you
about this case.
Alexa, what should I do
when an intern candidate
comes to my office all soaked?
Hello, tell her,
"You snooze, you lose."
I'm sorry. I overheard your conversation
about the squat.
I think I can help. I know someone inside.
I want you to talk with your connection
to find out how things work there,
but you must be discreet.
They can't know you work here.
The case is not ours yet. Not officially.
- Can you do this for me, Anna?
- Sure.
I'll deliver the report
as soon as possible.
- Great. That's the Anna Júlia we want.
- I won't let you down, Sophia.
I found you!
I made this thinking about you
Spooning Playlist
A playlist?
No, you won't convince me.
DON'T LET THE NO DISTRACT YOU,
SETTLE IN THE YES, LIKE TIM MAIA'S SONG
- Hey! I'm here!
- Relax. How are you?
You good?
I brought your key
to the room we'll share.
- Bed is made, sheets are clean...
- I can't thank you enough.
There's plenty of ways to thank me.
Debit, credit...
- Do I have to pay when I check in?
- When you get there.
But it's okay, right?
- Yeah, it's all right.
- Cool.
- Have a nice day at work.
- Peace.
- I like the laser beam!
- Thanks!
Your scarf was kidnapped
Ransom Lunch with me tomorrow
Scarf for autumn
New rug
80's musician headband
Attention, JP, that's enough. Stop it.
This recording is for you to stop tripping
and remember your ideas.
What if I write a song...
about a girl wearing a colorful scarf?
Who doesn't like music or rhymes.
What if I write a song about a girl...
I'm fixed on the girl idea.
I'm obsessed with her.
I wish I was Lulu. Hit after hit.
The true hit maker.
You're gonna be a hit maker, son!
You'll look at the bunkbed
and write a good song... on a bunkbed!
Help me, Lulu!
- Lulu?
- You called me?
- Lulu!
- JP, right? What's up?
How can I write a great song?
Have you eaten?
I could eat four of these.
- I use a smartphone app.
- Smartphones make you dumb.
Right?
The voice should be between the mind
and the heart. In the middle.
My mom, Lulu.
She used to say,
"I'll buy it later." These things hurt!
I'd like to be more confident
in front of people.
You know what? Feel it.
- Hold it.
- But let it go.
- Let it go!
- But hold it!
Three, four, two...
And the neck is steady. Floating,
smiling.
Again!
- JP for posterity.
- Heart to the sky.
Help me, Lulu!
Stop tripping, right, JP?
Hi. Excuse me. Good morning.
Good morning, girl!
You came! That's great!
Coming through. Don't forget the salt.
Right on time!
- You'll try my food.
- What an honor!
But help with that pan over there.
Then I'll show you around.
Come on, everyone!
What about our lunch?
I'll meet you.
I can't, João You're a musician
Musicians eat too.
That's why I'm here.
I think the office will take the case.
My boss didn't say much.
They take a lot of pro bono cases,
you know?
- Pro bono?
- When the client doesn't need to pay.
Nice, right?
What about you? What do you do?
I sing.
I know you sing, JP,
but how do you make a living?
That's my job. My main one.
Full time! All the time, since forever.
Until I die.
I don't believe
what you told me about the festival.
I think you can pull that off.
When we really want something,
we go get it. We focus.
Focus? I don't even know what that means.
Look over there.
I'll teach you.
You need a chart in your head,
like this plate.
You split it in sections
and focus on what's most important.
In this case...
the salad.
So, that's it.
I don't care much for lettuce.
I don't think anybody does, but we eat it
because we know it's good for our future.
I think life works like a huge hot dog.
- Hot dog?
- Hot dog.
What?
You may even have a recipe.
All the ingredients too,
- including bacon.
- Bacon?
- Jeez!
You know when you're starving
and would do anything for food?
It's dramatic!
You take the hot dog,
and the sausage jumps.
It falls out. The ketchup
stains your only pair of white pants.
- You know?
- Yeah.
It's sad!
And then...
the hot dog...
just flows.
Just like life.
There's no chart. There's no rule
that prepare us for this ride,
Anna Júlia.
Got it?
I have to go work.
Bye.
Bye!
The administration office.
There's paperwork,
resident documentation...
But I love it here.
This is my vegetable garden.
- Coming through!
- Good morning!
How are you, João?
Could you plant these?
Are you in charge of the administration?
- I take care of everything.
- Mom, Ms. Ida is feeling ill again.
Jussara took her to the ER,
but the kitchen is empty.
I can help.
Your father said you were hard-working.
Come on. We have six hands
to cook for 300 people.
I loved lunch
No problem. We can wait.
Sorry!
I
Missed you and cried
Today nothing else matters
I'm going through life
On this road of no return
I will never give up
Listening to my heart
Here each one is more than one
You have to smile
Each one is more than one
You have to cry
You have to say and you have to act
To work
To occupy
To resist
To conquer our home
I
Missed you and cried
Today nothing else matters
I'm going through life
On this road of no return
I will never give up
Listening to my heart
The drum beats in my chest
Here each one is more than one
Here everyone has value
Here there is no hurry and no color
It has flavor, it has knowledge
To walk
To welcome
And to win
I
Missed you and cried
Today nothing else matters
I'm going through life
On this road of no return
I will never give up
Listening to my heart
The drum beats in my chest
Here is the report for the first day.
Where is the info I requested?
It's in there.
- I've been there, and it's impressive.
- It's personal info.
I need objective info.
How their structure is,
what problems they're facing. Got it?
- That's not it!
- Right.
The coffee was great. Thanks so much.
- I'll sing. It'll blow your mind!
- Let's do it.
The guitar, the case on the ground
There's no money, no
Throw a dime, okay?
- Can I really be honest?
- Okay, mock me.
- You like to mock, go on.
- Keep on trying.
Anna?
What's all that, Dad?
What?